《第一滴血3》
(美国驻泰大使馆)
你认识他吗
Do you know him?
约翰
John!
请问约翰在哪儿
在那里
约翰
John
约翰·蓝波
John Rambo
真不敢相信
I don't believe this
你从哪里来
So where did you come from?
华府
Washington
很高兴再见到你
Good to see you again
我也是
Yeah,you too
你...要对我说说吗
You want to tell me about it?
说什么
About what?
昨天我看到了你
About yesterday I see you
在曼谷的棒棍战
stick fighting in a warehouse in Bangkok
你看到了
You saw that?
是的
Yeah.
而今天却见你在庙里工作
And today I find you working in a monastery
他们让我住在这里  而我帮忙修东西
They let me live here and I heIp out fixing things
棒棍战呢
And the stick fighting?
我只是挣点外快
I just do that for a little extra money
对  我看见你将钱交给和尚了
Yeah. I saw you give it to the monks
眼力不错
You see a Iot
上校  他们是谁
Colonel Who are they?
我来此的部份理由是为了他们
They're partly the reason I'm here
巴伯
Bob
这是罗伯·格雷
This is Robert Griggs
本地大使馆的校级军官
He's a fieId officer with local embassy
约翰·蓝波
John Rambo
幸会
Pleasure
你真不好找
You're certainly not easy to find
怎么  你要跟踪我吗
Why,are you keeping track?
正如上校所说
Like the Colonel says
行家不易找
Good men are hard to find
约翰  我要你看看这些照片
John I'd like you to look at some of these photos
我不知道你对阿富汗了解多少
I don't know how much you know about Afghanistan
很多人在地图上甚至都找不到它
Most people can't even find it on a map
但有超过二百万老百姓
But over two million civilians,
大部份是农民和其家人
mostly peasant farmers and their families
正被入侵的俄军
have been systematically slaughtered
有系统的屠杀
by invading Russian armies
每一种新武器
Every new weapon...
包括化学武器在内
Including chemical warfare
都在残害这些人
has been used to eliminate these people
他们在各方面都很成功
They've been very successful on many levels
我猜你已不大了解最新战况
I assume you're out of touch with the current status of the war
经过9年的战争
After nine years of fighting,
阿富汗军队己有了毒刺导弹
The Afghan Forces are now getting shipment of stinger missiles
并固守根据地进行反抗
They're beginning to hold their own against air strikes
只除了一个例外
Except for one region
那在距边界50英里的地方
50 miles over the border
很显然那里的俄军指挥官相当残忍
Apparently The Soviet commander there is exceptionally brutal
就如照片上显示一样
As those photos indicate
他切断所有外援
He's managed to strangle off all aid from the outside
所以  我们...
So,we want to ...
要有第一手的调查资料
investigate the problem first hand
这与我何关
What's that got to do with me?
他们要我去
They've asked me to go in
你不会去吧
You're not doing it?
不  而且我想你和我一起去  约翰
Yes. And I want you to come with me,John
我的期限已过
I put in my time
什么意思
What does that mean?
即是说我的战争已结束
It means my wars is over
亏你还说他是出色的军人
I thought you said he was a great soIdier
上校
Colonel
看来我们白跑一趟了
Looks like we got a long walk down those stairs
别生他的气  他只是奉命行事
Don't be down on him. He's just following orders
这个任务很重要  约翰
This mission's important,John
你真的认为我们可改变什么吗
Do you really think we'll make a difference?
不然我就不会去了
If I didn't,I wouldn't be going
我们从没改变过什么
It didn't before
今时不同往日
That was another time
跟我去  约翰
Come with me,John
我不知你觉得这里怎样
I don't know what you think about this place
但我喜欢这里
But I like it
我喜欢住这里  喜欢在这里工作
I like being here, I like working here
我喜欢有归属感
I like belonging to something
你确有归属
You do belong to something
但不是这里
Not this
你何时才能成为完人
When will you come full circle?
你说什么
What are you talking about?
你说你的战争己结束
You said your war is over
外界的战争也许如此  但你内心则不然
Maybe the one out there is,But not the one inside you
我知你为何来此  约翰
I know the reasons you're here,John
但这样不是办法
But it doesn't work that way
你可以尝试别样的生活
You may try,
但你无法逃避真正的你
but you can't get away what you really are
你认为真正的我是什么
What do you think that?
一个浴血战场的军人
A full-blooded combat soldier
不再是了  我不要这样
Not anymore. I don't want it
太可惜了  因为你注定是这种人
That's too bad because you're stuck with it
我给你讲个故事  约翰
Let me tell you a story,John
有个雕刻家  他发现了块石头
There was a sculptor,and he found a stone
很特别的石头
a special stone
他把它拖回家  努力多月
He dragged it home,worked on it for months,
终于完成了
until he finally finished it
他给他朋友看这石头
When he was ready to show it to his friends
他们说他创造了一件杰出的雕像
They said he'd created a great statue
雕刻家说他没创造出什么
The sculptor said he hadn't created anything
雕像早已在那
The statue was always there
他只是把多余部份清除掉而己
He just cleared away the small pieces
我们不是要将你训练成战争机器
We didn't' make you this fighting machine
我们只是显现你的本质
We just chipped away the rough edges
你若不想折腾自己
You're always be going to be tearing away at yourself
就要接受真正的你
until you come to terms with what you are
直至令自己完满
Until you come full circle
我想我还没准备好
I guess I'm not ready yet
我要启程了
Well. I got to move
答应我  安顿好就来找我
Promise me. You'll look me up,when you get stateside,huh?
我答应你
I promise
上校
Colonel
抱歉
I'm sorry
但有时我只是想要结束
But it's got to the end for me some time
我明白了
I understand
找掩护  开火
Take cover!Fire!
放下武器  待在原地
Drop your weapons!And remain where you are
你们逃不了
You cannot escape!
你们不逃  我们就不攻击
We will not attack if you do not run!
放下武器
Drop your weapons!
你们逃不掉的
You have no chance to escape!
放下武器
Drop your weapons!
马上
Now!
蓝波
Rambo
出事了
Something went wrong
怎么回事
What happened?
俄军在边界拦截了他们
Soviets intercepted the team just over the border
我们得到情报
From what we get it,
普曼和其其他人
Trautman and the rest of his party
被带到了指挥基地
have been taken to a regional command post
你们打算怎么办
What are you doing about it?
我们无能为力
We can't do anything about it
抱歉
I'm sorry
我只是觉得你该知道此事
I just thought you should know
我怎么样?
What about me?
什么你怎么样?
What about you?
能让我加入吗
Can you get me in?
你不是说真的吧
You're not serious
我很认真
Oh,yeah. I'm serious
正式方法行不通
It can't be done officially
那就用别的办法
Make it unofficial
如果你要加入
If you give it done
我得先告诉你
I want you to know up front that
假设你被捕
if you're captured
或这事走漏风声
or if any of this leaks,
我们会否认你有份参与
we'll deny any participation
也不会承认知道你的存在
or even knowledge of your existence
我习惯了
I'm used to it
我会再连络你
I'll get back to you
巴基斯坦  派夏渥
阿富汗边境附近
你要买吗
You want to buy?
这里有很多枪
Many guns here
不  我找默沙·拉尼
No I'm looking for Mousa Gani
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
约翰·蓝波
John Rambo
在这里等着
Wait here
这在阿富汗很畅销
They sell many in Afghanistan
很多地雷
Many land mines
到处都是地雷
Land mines everywhere
我是默沙·拉尼  你有什么事
I am Mousa Gani What is it you want?
我是格雷派来的
I was sent by Griggs
你不像格雷以前派来的人
You do not look like men Griggs sent before
你不像是军方的人
You not look like you are with military
我不是
I'm not
那你是什么
What you are?
佣兵吗
A mercenary?
不是
No
既非军人 也非佣兵  你是什么人
You're not military or mercenary What are you?
迷路的观光客?
Lost tourist?
我不是观光客
I'm no tourist
抱歉
Sorry
你知道美国人在哪里吗
Do you know where the American is?
知道  在俄军基地
Yes,In Soviet fort
贺斯村庄附近  离边境30英里远
Near the village of Khowst, 30 miles over border
格雷先生已送来你要的物资
Mr Griggs sent you supplies you asked for
你要现在看看吗
You wish to see them now?
好
Yeah
这是你要的吗
Is this what you asked for?
是
Yeah
我从未见过  这是什么
I never see this before. What are these?
雷管
Detonators
这个呢
And this?
这是做什么的
What is this for?
蓝光
It's a blue light
有什么用
What does it do?
变成蓝色
Turns blue
原来如此
I see
可否告诉我同行还有多少人
Can you tell me how many more men come with us?
没有救援队伍  只有我一人
There's no rescue team. It's just me
只有你  得了吧  这行不通
Just you? Come on,this is no good
我不能只带一人就去基地
I cannot take only one man to the fort
你需要更多帮手
You need more men to help
格雷说你会带我去  带我去吧
Griggs said you'd take me in. Take me in
我得带上药品
I need to take medical supplies
不然会死很多人
If I not take it,many peopIe will die
明白吗
Do you understand?
蓝波  我并不清楚你究竟是谁
Rambo,I do not know who you really are
但看你的样子就知道
But by the way you look,
你是个菜鸟
I can see you have no experience in war,
没错吧
do you?
说呀  是不是
Come on,do you?
我曾开过几枪
I've fired a few shots
几枪?
A few shots?
得了吧  也许你该回家去
Come on Maybe you should go back home
再考虑下
And think it all over again
好好想清楚
for a very long time
我己考虑过了
I did think it over
是吗
You did?
这是你的抉择  但我告诉你
This is your choice. But let me tell you
你单枪匹马是救不了那美国人
You cannot get this American alone
如果失败  别怪我
If you fail,do not blame me
我可不负责
I will accept no responsibility
听过多次了
Sounds familiar
我是赛生上校
My name is Colonel Zaysen,
这个地区的指挥官
the Regional Commander of this sector
你可知道  你是首个在阿富汗
Do you realize,you're the first American
被抓的美国人
captured in Afghanistan?
恭喜
Congratulations!
我相信你们正计划提供
I believe you are planning to supply
毒刺导弹给叛军
enemy rebel forces with stinger missiles
企图摧毁俄空军
intended to destroy Soviet aircraft
若我要被拷问
If I'm going to be interrogated,
找你的上司来
I want to be interrogated by your superiors
在这里  我最大
Out here,I have no superiors
这里由我全权负责
I am in full command
你是孤立无援的
You are alone here
你被你的政府离弃
Abandoned by your government
你想怎样
What do you want?
合作
Cooperation
这个地区五年多来
This sector has been under total control
一直被完全控制
for over five years.
我在这己无甚可做
There is little more I can do here
就像你们所说
It is as you say
己没有了挑战性
Without challenges
如果你能告诉我关于
If you supply to me worthy information
你们导弹供应计划的情报
about more stinger missiles you are planning to deliver
这对你我二人都有好处
it could provide a way out of this for us both
毕竟  大家最终想要的都是
After all,in the end,what everyone really wants is...
和平
Peace
俄政府还真幽默
The Kremlin's got a sense of humor
为什么
PIease explain
你们向世界宣扬和平  军备裁减
You talk peace and disarmament to the world
却在这里进行种族屠杀
And here you are wiping out a race of people
我们没有屠杀任何人
We are wiping out no one
你们居然如此愚蠢
I think you are too intelligent
相信那些荒谬宣传
to believe such absurd propaganda
再问一次  导弹在哪里
Now again,where are the missiles?
我对导弹的事一概不知
I don't know anything about any missiles
你当然知道  但你似乎不了解
Of course you do. But you don't seem to realize
我正为你我二人寻找出路
I'm providing a way out for us both.
你在寻求同情吗
You expect sympathy?
战争是你们挑起的
You started this damn war!
你们得自己去收拾残局
Now you have to deal with it!
我们当然会
And we will
全面胜利只是迟早问题
It's just a matter of time before we achieve a complete victory
根本不会有胜利
There won't be a victory!
你们的战争机器每天都输给
Every day your war machines lose ground to a bunch of
那些装备简陋的自由斗士
poorly armed, poorly equipped freedom fighters
事实上  你低估了对手实力
The fact is you underestimated your competition
你若读过历史
If you studied the history,
便知这些人从不屈服
you will know these people have never given up to anyone
他们宁死  也不愿成奴隶
They'd rather die,than be slaves
成为侵越者的奴隶
to an invading army
你打不倒这样的人
You can't defeat a people like that
我们试过了  在越南已试过了
We tried,We already had our Vietnam
现在轮到你们了
Now you're going to have yours
你要考验我  好
So,you wish to test me!Good
这就是阿富汗
This is Afghanistan
亚历山大大帝曾尝试征服这片国土
Alexander The Great tried to conquer this country
之后是成吉思汗  英国人
Then Genghis Khan,then the British
现在是俄国人
Now Russia
但阿富汗人誓死反抗
But Afghan people fight hard
他们永远打不倒
They'll never be defeated
古代的敌人作祷词歌颂这些人
Ancient enemy make prayer about these people
你想听吗
You wish to hear?
好  是这样的
Very good. It says:
愿神让我们远离眼镜蛇之毒
May God deliver us from the venom of the cobra
老虎之齿  和阿富汗人的复仇之心
Teeth of the tiger And the vengeance of the Afghan
明白它的含义吗
You understand what this means?
你们绝对不会屈服?
That you guys don't take any shit?
没错  差不多
Yes. Something like this
我们走吧
We go now
北方有很多山洞
To the north,there are many caves,
我们由那里走
We will travel through them,
那样安全点  走吧
It'll be safer,We go
这些山洞通往五狮村
These caves lead us to the valley of five lions
古时  有人要求阿富汗国王
In ancient days,the Afghan king was asked
出兵五百
to send 500 warriors into battle
他说  只出兵五名
He said:Only five
那是精兵中的精兵  结果凯旋而归
His greatest five and they won
他说  宁派五头狮子  莫派五百绵羊
He said: It's better to send five lions than 500 sheep
你觉得呢
What do you think of this?
我认为国王很走运
I think the king was lucky
走运哈
Lucky?
还要多久才到村庄
How much longer to the village?
约两小时
About two hours
导弹要运到哪里
Where in my sector are the missiles being delivered?
我不知道
I don't know
你说谎
You're a liar
哪里
Where?
好  我说
All right. I tell you
我就知道你说谎
I knew you were lying
现在告诉我  导弹在哪里
Now,where are the missiles located?
很近
Close
多近
How close?
近在你屁眼里
In your ass
你考验我的耐性己够久了
You've tried my patience long enough
我也想客气一点
I tried to be civilized
约翰·蓝波
The name of John Rambo
你认识吗
Do you know it?
不认识吗
No
他说  有人在叛军协助下
He says there are plans for a rescue attempt
打算劫狱
with the help of some rebels
他还说知道这人的去向
He also says he knows where this man is going
我们会好好招待他
We will welcome him
这是山谷中最后一个村庄
It's the last village in the valley
大约有一百人
About 100 men here
这里有很多小孩
They have a lot of kids here
对  他们也都是出色的战士
Yes. And they are good fighters,too
我去跟首领说我们要谈谈
I tell the leaders we want to talk
他们从未见过像你这样的人
They never see man look like you
他们是默斯汀的骑士
These are Mujahedeen horsemen
边界还有一万骑士在等候
There're 10000 horsemen more waiting at the border
他们在等着拿武器
They are waiting to get weapons.
一旦到手  就回来战斗
When they get it,they come back here to fight
我们去医院吧
Let's go to the hospital
他是方圆五百里内唯一的医生
He's the only doctor for 500 kilometers
他们两个月内第一次拿到药品
The first medicine they get in two months
俄军送来很多礼物
More gifts from the Soviets
看来像玩具  但其实是地雷
They look like toys,but they are mines
我们教导孩子别去碰  但有时已太迟
We teach children not to touch,Some learn too late
那是谁
Who's that?
他叫约里  是俄国人
His name is Uri. He's Russian
逃兵吗
Deserter?
他自称投降者
He call himself a Defector
这有很多他这样的人
There are many like him
他能帮很多忙
He's the one who can help the most
他知道堡内的情况
He knows the inside of the fort
我想我们该走了
I think we should go now
地雷从这里开始
Mine starts here
像这样一米
At 1 meter like this
然后像这样有二米
Then go 2 meters like this and like this
有四个塔台  四个哨兵
They have four towers,Four guards
这里  这里  这里和这里
Here,here,here and here
犯人关在哪里
Where they keep the prisoners?
这里
Here
进去后  有其他出口吗
If we get in there,is there another way out?
地下  满是臭水的地方
Underground,where is all bad water
我不知道那该叫作什么
I do not know words for this place
他是说污水道
He means sewer
在哪里
Where is it?
这里  通到外面的那边
Here,Outside,it goes there
有哨兵巡逻
Guards patrol there
我认为你不该走这条路
I do not think you go this way
那我们走雷区  他们不会巡逻
We should go through the mine fields,They will not expect it
不行  那里有很多地雷
This cannot be done .There are many spetnaz commandos
我们只剩下这些人
We are only these
我们损失了很多人
We have lost many men
如果再去  会损失更多
We lose many more if we go there
我不需很多人
I don't need many men
你打算怎么做
What is it that you want to do?
我需要两人带我穿过雷区
I need two men to get me into the mine field
两人协助我逃走
And two to help me to escape
这样做的话
If this is done
俄军会像从前一样来这里
Soviets will come here like before
会死更多人
And more peopIe will die
我等不了
I can't wait
你要像我们一样等待救援
You must wait for help,the way we wait
那我一个人去
Then I'll go alone
你会死
And you will die
那就死吧
Then I die
等等
Wait!
请你别去
Please don't go!
我名叫拉苏
My name is Masoud
在了解我们为何不能帮你前
You must not judge us
请别对我们妄下判断
before you understand why we are not ready to help
大部分阿富汗人都很坚强
Most of the Afghan people are very strong
我们决意不能被逐离自己的土地
And we are determined not to be driven from our land
我们的孩子病死  炸死
Our children die of disease,mines
给毒气毒死
and poison gas.
妇女惨遭奸杀
And the women are raped and killed
去年  邻谷的依拉洛格曼
Last year,in the valley of Laghman,the next valley,
6千阿富汗人被杀害
6000 Afghans were killed
怀孕妇女被破肚开肠
Pregnant women were cut with bayonets
婴孩被丢入火中
and their babies thrown into the fires
他们这样做
This is done,
是为了斩草除根
so they will not have to fight the next generation of Afghans
但报章杂志不会有任何报导
Yet nobody sees anything or reads anything in the papers
你现在所见
What you see here
是默斯汀战士
are the Mujahedeens soldiers
神圣的战士
Holy warriors
对我们而言  这是场圣战
To us,this war is a Holy war
默斯汀战士是打不死的
And there's no true death for a Mujahedeen
因为我们己发过毒誓
because we have taken our last rites
视死如归
We consider ourselves dead already
于我们  为土地和神灵而忘是荣誉
To us, death for our land and God is an honor
所以  朋友
So,my friend
我们所要做的是
What we must do
保护我们的妻儿
is to stop this killing of our women and children
若能救出那人
If getting this man free,
让他回到自由世界
so he can return to the free world
告诉别人这里发生的事情
and tell what happens here is necessary
我们当然会帮忙
then of course,we will heIp
离开吧
Leave us now
让我们自己商量
So we may speak among ourseIves
救出那人的最佳方法
and find the best way to free this man
谢谢你
Thank you
我们感谢你
We thank you
放心  他们很快会有决定
Don't worry.They will decide soon
今晚必须进去
Got to get in tonight
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
这小孩非常坚强
This boy is very hard inside
他父母去年被杀
His parents were killed last year
他哥哥死在那美国人被关押的地方
His brother died in the fort where the American is
他虽是小孩  却如男子汉般战斗
He looks like a boy,but he fights like a man
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
蓝波
Rambo
你从哪里来
Where are you from?
亚历桑纳
Arizona
亚历桑纳?  要走几天路?
Arizona?How much days' walk?
约两年
About two years
你是军人吗
Are you a soldier?
曾经是
No more
我是军人  你准备好战斗了吗
I am a soldier.Are you ready to fight?
没有
No
你怕吗
Are you scared?
这是什么
What is this?
是刀
It's a knife
- 能看看吗  - 当然可以
- Can I see this? - Sure
很棒  能给我吗
Very good. Can I have it?
不能
No.
这是什么
What is this?
你什么都想要  这会带来好运
You want everything.This is for luck
什么是好运
What is luck?
好运是...
Luck is...
能给我吗  我需要运气
Can I have it? I need luck
我也需要
So do I
这小孩
Look at this child,
他总是这样
aIways like this
看那  国民运动
Look there,it's a national sport
又老又蠢的游戏  也许有三千年历史了
Old insane game. Maybe 3000 years old
看啊  他们总玩那个
Look,They never stop playing it
打不打仗  他们不在乎
War,not war,they don't mind
喜欢吗
You like it?
我宁愿打橄榄球
I'll take football
橄榄球  什么是橄榄球
Football? What's football?
用脚玩吗
You play with your foot?
不完全是
Not really
来  我们走吧
Come on. Come on. Let's go
美国人
Hey,American!
他们说什么
What are they saying?
他们想你也去
They want you to try
这是欢迎你的方式
It's a way to welcome you to go with 'em.
想玩就去吧
If you want to try,go ahead
但出什么事  我可不负责
But I'm not responsibIe for it
我试试
I'll try
是吗
Yes?
规则是什么
What are the rules?
你带着羊绕一圈
You have take the sheep once a round
然后丢在圈中
and then throw it in the circle
为什么
Why?
因为那边有个圈
Because there is a circle there
就这样吗
That's it?
就这样  很简单
That's it. Very simple
像橄榄球
Like football
神一定很喜欢傻子
God must love crazy people
为什么
Why?
要不他也不会造那么多出来
He makes so many of them
找掩护  找掩护
Take cover! Take cover!
现在你看到了
Now you see how it is here
战斗本该是为荣誉而为
Somewhere in war,there's supposed to be honor
可荣誉呢  在哪呢
Where is the honor here? Where?
我们带幸存者去边境  你来吗
We are taking the survivors to the border. Are you coming?
我要去军营
I'm going to the fort
你见到的死亡还不够吗
Have you not seen enough death?
走吧  趁还可以  离开吧
Go,go while you can
这不是你的战争
This is not your war
现在是了
It is now
就好吧
So be it
你是我们的好朋友
You are a good friend
我留下  我给你带路
I stay. I will show you the way
我也去
I will go,too
不  你和他们走
No. You go with them
不  他们杀光我全家  我要作战
I will not.They kill all my family. I want to fight
和我一起不行
Not with me
你走
You go
去呀
Come on
你为什么一定要这样做
Why must you do this?
因为他也会为我这样做
Because he'd do it for me
你决定要招了吗
Have you decided to talk?
还是不吗
No?
非常好
Very well
很快你将成为阎王爷的座上客
Soon you will be my guest down the hall
来吧
Come on
回去
Go back!
不
No
回去
Go back!
走
Go on
待在这里  留在后面
Stay here. Stay back
我熟悉这个地方  你需要我
I know this place.You need me
我不需要你死  回去  明白吗
I don't need you dead.Go back! Understand?
美国人
The American
上校  上校  上校
CoIonel? CoIonel? CoIonel?
约翰  你怎么进来的
John,how the hell did you get in here?
你能走吗
Can you move?
当然可以
You're damn right,I can
我们走
Let's go
约翰  小心身后
John,behind you!
走
Go!
约翰  离开这里  快离开
John! Get out! Get the hell out of here!
快走
Go on!
这边
Over here!
快
Come on!
帮我
Help me!
带他走
Take him
跟上
Come on!
把孩子给我
Give me the boy
快点
Hurry!
过来
Come on!
好
OK
带着孩子
Take the kid
跳下去
Get down!
长官  部队已经做好准备了
立刻去追他们
来
Come!
把孩子给我
Give me the boy
这个家伙是谁
Who is the terrorist?
你和他有什么关系
What makes you so valuable to him?
这王八蛋今晚想毁了我
This bastard tried to destroy me tonight
但他失败了  太阳升起前我会抓到他
But he failed! At sunrise,I'll hunt him down
把他的皮剥了挂在墙上
and have his skin hang on the wall!
你不必去抓他
You don't have to hunt him
什么
What?
他会来找你
He'll find you
你疯了吗
Are you insane?
一对三十?
One man against thirty commandos?
你以为他是谁
Who do you think this man is?
神吗
God?
神大慈大悲  他更厉害
No. God would have mercy. He won't
没事了  这儿没人了
It's alright,nobody's here
好  可以歇一下了
All right. This will hoId a while
哪条路能最快离开这里
What's the fastest way out of here?
西北方有条山径
Northwest, There is trail between mountains
离这里三公里远
about 3 kilometers from here
山径很难走
The trail is very difficult
你带男孩走
You take the boy and go
我要留下
I want to stay
不行
You can't
你不能再回去
You cannot go back there
我们必须一起去巴基斯坦
We must all go to Pakistan
不  我必须回去
I've got to go back
我知他是你的朋友  但你不能这么做
I know he's your friend,but you cannot do this
你俩都会死  值得吗
You both will die,for what?
跟我们走
Come with us
照我的话做
Just do what I say
枪给我
Give me your gun
好  走吧
Alright,let's go
来
Come on
我能再见你吗
I see you again?
当然
Sure
搜索该地区
收到
没有他的踪迹  长官
继续搜索美国人  我去加油
快点  走
Come on,move!
快
Come on!
你会开那个吗
Can you fly that thing?
试试看
Let's find out
我们走
Let's go!
快点  快点  上去
Hurry! Hurry!Get on board!
抓紧
Hold on!
那边
Over there!
There!
抓紧
Hold on!
上来
Get up!
抓我的手
Take my hand!
我们要降落了
We're going down!
抓紧
Hold on!
快出去
Get out of here!
要爆炸了
It's going to blow!
尽量多拿点  约翰
Take what you can,John!
快点  快点
Come on! Move it! Move it!
别停
Go on!
我们必须去边界
We've got to get to the border
我们就待在这
We'll stay here
我们知道该去哪
We know where to go
哪个方向  约翰
Which direction,John?
东北方
Northeast
我要所有人做好准备
不能让他们到达边境
等等  约翰
Hold it,John
我必需休息一下
I've got to rest a minute
伤口如何
How's the wound?
你教我们别理会痛楚  不是吗
You taught us to ignore pain,didn't you?
有用吗
Is it working?
不尽然
Not really
不是针对你
Don't take it personally
谢了
Thanks
你先走  看能否找到掩护
You go on ahead and see if you can get a cover
好
Ok!
约翰
John!
好险  约翰  你还好吗
That was close,John,how are you?
干的好
Well-done
我们最好分头行事  给他们点厉害
We don't want to make it easy for them. We better split up
抱歉把你牵入进此事
I'm sorry I got you into this
你没有
No,you're not
史比纳兹  立刻回报
你听得见吗
Are you listening?
你是谁
Who are you?
你的恶梦
Your worst nightmare
库纳夫  下面到底是怎么了
时间抓的真准
That's good timing
不然你以为朋友用来干啥
What are friends for?
你回到洞里  我掩护你  看看还有没有人
You get back to the hole. I'll cover you and see if there's any left
扬克夫  回基地
约翰
John!
过了山谷就是边境
Across the valley is the border
我们成功了  约翰
We did it,John
对
Yeah
等等
Wait
那是什么
What the hell is that?
狗娘养的
The son of a bitch
不要企图逃跑
Do not try to retreat
你们逃不掉的
You cannot escape
你们不跑  我们就不会攻击
We won't attack if you do not run
我们不想伤害你们
We don't want to hurt you
不知怎的  我不相信他
Somehow I don't believe him
我命令你们向前
I order you to come forward
你们会接受公平的审判
You will receive a fair trial
放下武器  待在原地
Drop you weapons. And remain where you are
想到办法了吗
You got any ideas?
放下武器
Drop your weapons
包围他们
Surrounding them is out
你真会挑时间幽默  约翰
Hell of a time for humor,John
放下武器  马上
Drop the weapons. Now!
你们没有逃走的机会
You have no chance to escape!
向前走
Come forward
我也想活捉你们
I wish to take you back alive
这是最后警告
This is your last warning
你们自己选择
The choice is yours
你说如何  约翰
What do you say?
干掉他们
Fuck them!
要死  也要带那王八蛋一起死
If we're going,I wish we'd taken that bastard with us
那是什么
What is that?
是起义军队
It's the rebels
走吧
Come on!
约翰  快离开
John,get out of there!
约翰
John!
你真的不打算留下来吗
You sure you don't want to stay?
以一名观光客来说  你很会打仗
You fight good for a tourist
也许下次吧
Maybe next time
你要拿回这个吗
You want this back?
不  你留着
No. You keep it
你不能留下吗
Can you not stay?
我必需走
I've got to go
再见
Goodbye
难以置信
Hard to believe,John
怎么了  长官
What's that,sir?
我很不愿承认  但老实说
I hate to admit it,but the truth is,
我觉得我们开始害怕了
I think we're getting soft
也许只是一点点  长官
Maybe just a little,sir
只有一点点
Just a little
[本片谨献给英勇的阿富汗人民]